A Guide to the Papers of James Madison, ca. 1765-1836
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- C[harles]. Bonnycastle to James Madison 1827 March 30, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed; silked. (Box 2)
- Alexander Garrett to James Madison 1827 April 9, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 2)
- James Madison to Alexander Garrett 1827 April 18, AL, 2 pp. on 1 l.; mounted; silked. Draft. (Box 2)
- James Madison to Alexander Garrett 1827 April 18, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed; silked. (Box 2)
- Alexander Garrett to James Madison 1827 May 3, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. Also contains a copy [by James Madison] of a letter from T. J. Randolph to the Visitors of the University negotiations for a loan. (Box 2)
- T. Clowes to James Madison 1827 May 4, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed; silked. (Box 2)
- Thomas C. Levins to James Madison 1827 May 7, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- [James Madison] to Alexander Garrett 1827 May 11, AL, 1 p. (Box 2)
- James Madison to Alexander Garrett 1827 May 11, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; silked. (Box 2)
- John C. Calhoun to James Madison 1827 May 13, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- Nath. Bowditch to James Madison 1827 May 18, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- John A. Dix to James Madison 1827 May 20, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- Reverend Timothy Clowes to James Madison 1827 May, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- James Madison to John Hartwell Cocke 1827 May 27, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- James Madison to Joseph C. Cabell 1827 May 27, LS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- James Monroe to James Madison 1827 May 30, ALS, 1 p.; docketed; photocopy. (Box 2)
- W. A. Hatch to James Madison 1827 June 4, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- Reverend Thomas C. Levins to James Madison 1827 June 14, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- Alex Macomb, Engineering Department to James Madison 1827 June 18, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; docketed. (Box 2)
- Alfred H. Powell to James Madison 1827 June 20, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- James Madison to C.D. Cleveland 1827 June 22, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. (Box 2)
- John Hartwell Cocke to James Madison 1827 June 23, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- Nath[aniel] Bowditch to James Madison 1827 June 25, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- Resolutions of the Rector and Board of Visitors, University of Virginia 1827 July 10-19, AD, 38 pp. on 28 l.; with cover page. (Box 2)
- Alex[ander] Garrett to Mr. Madison 1827 July 11, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 2)
- James Madison to John Hartwell Cocke 1827 August 3, ALS, 1 p.; docketed; with copy of letter from Nicholas P. Trist. (Box 2)
- James Madison to Nicholas Trist 1827 August 4, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
  #11201
- James Madison to A.S. Brockenbrough 1827 August 23, ALS, 1 p.; docketed; Barrow. (Box 2)
- James Madison to [John Hartwell] Cocke 1827 September 5, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- James Madison to [John Hartwell] Cocke 1827 September 24, LS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed; also includes draft of letter [Cocke to Madison], 1827 October 8 (AL, 1 p.). (Box 2)
- James Madison to [Joseph C. Cabell] 1827 September 24, LS, 1 p.; docketed; enclosed letter Professor Long to James Madison, 1827 September 10 (AL, 2 pp.on 1 l.). (Box 2)
- James Madison to [John Hartwell] Cocke 1827 October 21, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- James Madison to A.S. Brockenbrough 1827 October 29, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 2)
- James Madison to [John Hartwell Cocke] 1827 November 2, ALS, 1 p.; in the hand of Dolley Madison. (Box 2)
- James Madison to Alexander Garrett 1827 November 3, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf, docketed; silked. (Box 2)
- George Ticknor to James Madison 1827 November 9, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
  #8553
- Matthew Carey to James Madison 1827 November 17, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed; silked. (Box 2)
  #38-458
- James Madison to [John Hartwell Cocke] 1827 November 19, LS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; in unidentified hand; docketed. (Box 2)
- James Madison to A.S. Brockenbrough 1827 November 24, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed; Barrow. (Box 2)
- James Madison to A.S. Brockenbrough 1827 December 2, ALS, 1 p.; docketed; Barrow. (Box 2)
- James Madison to [John Hartwell Cocke] 1827 December 3, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- James Madison to John Hartwell Cocke 1827 December 4, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 2)
- James Madison to Henry Brougham 1828 January 5, AL (draft), 1 p.; Barrow. (Box 3)
  #8544
- James Madison to James Breckenridge 1828 January 8, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed; portion of right center margin torn away, affecting text. (Box 3)
  #RG- 1/3/3.841
- University of Virginia bond signed by James Madison 1828 January 28, DS, 2 items, each partially printed, with an image of the Rotunda, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box 3)
  $500 bonds, numbered 26 and 27; for funds borrowed by the University from "Thomas Jefferson Randolph, trustee of Mrs. Martha Randolph." #8123
- James Madison to Littleton Dennis Teakle 1828 January 30, ALS, 1 p.; mounted. (Box 3)
- James Madison to James Monroe 1828 February 5, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
  #2832, Tracy W. McGregor Library
- James Madison to Albert Gallatin 1828 February 14, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; in the hand of Dolley Madison. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Robley Dunglison 1828 February 14, AL (draft), 1 p.; in the hand of Dolley Madison. (Box 3)
- Albert Gallatin to James Madison 1828 February 27, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf. (Box 3)
  #RG-1/3/3.803
- James Madison to Alexander Garrett 1828 March 4, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed; silked. (Box 3)
- James Madison to General [John Hartwell] Cocke 1828 March 9, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to William B. Laurence 1828 March 15, AL (draft), 2 pp. on 1 l. in the hand of Dolley Madison; Barrow. (Box 3)
- James Madison to [Joseph C. Cabell] 1828 March 27, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; Barrow. (Box 3)
  #4646, Tracy W. McGregor Library
- W.B. Lawrence to [James Madison] 1828 April 4, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. (Box 3)
- James Madison to General [John Hartwell] Cocke 1828 April 4, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison Alexander Garrett 1828 April 5, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed; silked. (Box 3)
- James Madison to C. Johnston [Chapman Johnson] 1828 May 1, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; in the hand of Dolley Madison. (Box 3)
- James Madison to General [John Hartwell] Cocke 1828 May 12, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to [A.S. Brockenbrough] 1828 June 21, ALS, 1 p.; docketed; Barrow. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Dr. James Wallace 1828 June 24, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; Barrow. (Box 3)
  #2318, Tracy W. McGregor Library
- James Madison to Mr. Brockenbrough 1828 July 31, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to General [John Hartwell] Cocke 1828 August 18, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Joseph C. Cabell 1828 August 18, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to General [John Hartwell] Cocke 1828 November 10, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- James S. Barbour to [James Madison] 1828 November 13, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box 3)
- N. Ferron to [James] Madison 1828 November 14, ALS(in French), 1 p.; translation included. (Box 3)
- James Madison to General [John Hartwell] Cocke 1828 November 15, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- John Hartwell Cocke to James Madison 1828 November 24, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to General [John Hartwell] Cocke 1828 November 29, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- Thomas Jefferson Randolph to James Madison 1828 December 7, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
  #2162
- James Madison to Alexander Garrett 1828 December 11, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed; silked. (Box 3)
- James Barbour to [James] Madison 1828 December 22, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf. (Box 3)
- James Madison to [Thomas Jefferson Randolph] 1828 December 22, ALS, 1 p.; photocopy. (Box 3)
  #6195
- James Madison to General [John Hartwell] Cocke 1828 December 24, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- G[eorge] Long to James Madison 1828 December, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Joseph C. Cabell 1829 January 5, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- Promissory note signed by James Madison to Charles J. Nourse 1829 January 27, DS, 1 p. (Box 3)
  #10029-e
- A.S. Brockenbrough to [James Madison] 1829 January 31, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to James Barbour 1829 February 6, AL, 2 pp. on 1 l.;docketed; Barrow. (Box 3)
- Robert Dunglison to James Madison 1829 February 19, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- [James Madison] to [John Hartwell Cocke] 1829 February 23, L, 1 p.; in Dolley Madison's? hand. (Box 3)
- James Madison to General [John Hartwell Cocke] 1829 February 23, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- Robert Dunglison to James Madison 1829 February 25, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 3)
- De Generes De Jourville to James Madison 1829 March 10, ALS, 1 p.; docketed; includes ANS, answer by James Madison. (Box 3)
- William Wertenbaker to James Madison 1829 March 13, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Joseph C. Cabell 1829 March 19, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Brockenbrough 1829 May 4, ALS, 1 p.; docketed; Barrow. (Box 3)
- James Madison to General [John Hartwell] Cocke 1829 May 8, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to General [John Hartwell] Cocke 1829 June 5, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; Barrow. (Box 3)
  #640-1480
- [James Madison] to George Long 1829 June 8, ALS, 2 pp.; draft. (Box 3)
- James Pleasants 1829 July 2, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- George W. Spotswood to [James Madison] 1829 July 4, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
  Resigning his position as hotel keeper. #11958.
- James Madison to Henry Dearborn 1829 August 28, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 3)
  Madison writes to acknowledge the honorary membership conferred upon him by the "Massachusetts Horticultural Society." #6078-a
- James Madison to Robley Dunglison 1829 September 15, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 3)
  #5503
- James Madison to General [John Hartwell] Cocke, LS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed; in Dolley Madison's hand. (Box 3)
- James Madison to John Tayloe Lomax 1830 January 30, ALS (draft), 1 p. (Box 3)
  #3635
- James Madison to Joseph C. Cabell 1830 January 30, LS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed; in Dolley Madison's hand. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Thomas S. Grinkle 1830 February 3, AL, 1 p.; draft. (Box 3)
  #10428-q
- James Madison to [William] Wertenbaker 1830 February 27, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; silked. (Box 3)
- George A. Smith to John H. Lee 1830 March, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Joseph Cabell 1830 April 10, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed; Barrow. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Senator Johnston of Louisiana 1830 May 14, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf. (Box 3)
  #3888
- A.S. Brockenbrough to James Madison 1830 July 21, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Joseph C. Cabell 1830 September 12, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; Barrow. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Thomas S. Grimke 1830 October 23, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
  #11148
- James Madison to Mr. Maxwell 1830 December 21, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. (Box 3)
  #2804, Tracy W. McGregor Library
- [John] Marshall to [James] Madison [ca. 1830], ALS, 1 p.; mounted. (Box 3)
  #4656-c
- James Madison to Joseph C. Cabell 1831 February 9, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed; silked. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Reverend Frederick Beasley 1831 March 22, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed; negative photocopy. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Robley Dunglison 1831 April 22, AL, 2 pp. on 1 l.; copy in Dolley Madison's hand; Barrow. (Box 3)
  #6002
- James Madison to Joseph C. Cabell 1831 April 25, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Consul James Maury 1831 April 29, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- Philip Barbour to James Madison 1831 April, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf (fragment). (Box 3)
  #5482-c
- James Madison to Thompson and Homans 1831 July 5, ALS, 1 p.; mounted. (Box 3)
  #3635-a
- James Madison to Joseph C. Cabell 1831 July 11, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Robert M. Patterson 1831 October 6, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Nicholas P. Trist 1831 December 21, L, 1 p.; copy in unidentified hand. (Box 3)
  #657
- William Madison to Colonel J[ames] Madison 1832 March 6, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
  #38-672
- James Madison to M. Le Roy de Chaumant 1832 June 9, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Thomas Jefferson Randolph 1832 July 6, LS, 1 p. (Box 3)
  #5093
- James Madison to Robley Dunglison 1832 November 10, ALS, 1 p.; docketed; Barrow. (Box 3)
  #3743
- [Reuben] Conway to James Madison 1832 December 21, ALS, 1 p.; docketed; Barrow. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Martin Van Buren 1833 February 14, AL, 1 p. (Box 3)
  #5316
- James Madison to John Hartwell Cocke 1833 May 16, LS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed; copy of letter from [Robley] Dunglison to James Madison (1 p.) on verso; both in the hand of Dolley Madison. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Joseph C. Cabell 1833 May 16, LS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed; copy of letter from Robley Dunglison to James Madison, 1833 May 14 (1 p.) on verso; both? in the hand of Dolley Madison? (Box 3)
- Chapman Johnson to James Madison 1833 June 6, ALS, 2 pp.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- Robley Dunglison to [James Madison] 1833 June 24, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Joseph C. Cabell 1833 July 14, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed; in the hand of Dolley Madison. (Box 3)
- Engraving of James Madison by T.B. Welch from a drawing by J.B. Longacre 1833 July, 1 p. (Box 3)
- James Madison to William Pendleton 1833 September 18, LS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed; in the hand of Dolley Madison. (Box 3)
- William Allen to James Madison 1833 November 15, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Joseph C. Cabell 1833 December 1, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Princess Victoria 1834 February 1, ANS, 1 p.; Barrow. (Box 3)
  #4506
- James Shepherd to James Madison 1834 June 14, ANs, 1 p. (Box 3)
- James Madison to D.A. Hall 1834 August 8, AL, 1 p.; draft. (Box 3)
  #6764
- James Madison to [?] 1834 September 20, LS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box 3)
  #5589
- James Madison to James L. Catheart [1834], ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; draft; Barrow. (Box 3)
  #5233
- James Madison to Joseph C. Cabell 1835 July 2, LS, 1 p.; with address leaf; docketed. (Box 3)
- Joseph C. Cabell to James Madison 1835 July 25, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box 3)
  #383
- J.C. Payne to David Weaver 1835 September 21, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Andrew Jackson 1835 October 11, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; draft. (Box 3)
  #5482-g
- James Madison to Professor Palfrey 1835 November 7, AL, 1 p.; draft. (Box 3)
  #2598
- Daniel G. Hickey to James Madison 1836 March 1, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. (Box 3)
- James Madison to B.W. Leigh 1836 May 1, ALS, 1 p.; in unidentified hand. (Box 3)
  #1395
- Virgil Davis to James Madison 1836 May 6, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Mr. Buck [n.y., Feb. 11], ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address leaf; docketed; postmarked Farmville, Va. Feb. 11. (Box 3)
  #6290
- James Madison to Thompson and Homens [n.y.] July 3, AL, 1 p.; fragment. (Box 3)
- James Madison to Stephen Pleasonton [n.y.] August 23, ANS, 1 p. (Box 3)
  #495
- Invitation to Mr. and Mrs. [Joseph] Nourse [n.y.] November 12, D, 1 p.; completed in unidentified hand; Barrow (Box 3)
- James Madison to Dolley Madison [n.d.], ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf. (Box 3)
- Envelope franked by James Madison [n.d.] (Box 3)